Inventory of the Daingerfield Papers 1833-1930
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Daingerfield Papers, 1833-1851
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.2 D14
8 items.
Letters of Mrs. Sallie Withrow Daingerfield to family members. Includes letters from Edward Randolph Edmunds.
Daingerfield Family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 31 March 1930.
Scope and Content Information
Letters, 1833-1840, from Sallie Withrow Daingerfield at "Belleplane" [or "Belleplain"] Richmond County, Va. to her husband Joseph F. Daingerfield, member of the Virginia House of Delegates; to her sister Margaret A. Withrow at Lewisburg, Greenbrier County, Va. [now W. Va.]; and to her brother John Withrow.
Includes letters, 1850-1851, from Edward Randolph Edmunds in London, Eng. and Florence, Italy to his sister Sallie Edmunds (Mrs. Edwin Short Edmunds) describing his travels; and a letter, 1930, concerning the military service of Joseph F. Daingerfield.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Organization
The inventory has been divided into three series. Series 1 are the letters of S. M. Daingerfield, series 2 are letters of Edward R. Edmunds and series 3 is a letter concerning the West Point record of Joseph F. Daingerfield.
Index Terms
Persons:
Daingerfield, Joseph F., 1800 or 1-1840.; Daingerfield, Sallie Withrow.; Withrow, Margaret A.; Withrow, John.; Edmunds, Edward Randolph.; Edmunds, Sallie, Mrs.
Contents List
  Series 1: Letters of S. M. Daingerfield
- Letters of S. M. Daingerfield. 1833-1840., 5 items.
  - S. M. Daingerfield at Lewisburg, [Va.] to Joseph F. Daingerfield, at Fayette Court House, Va. 17 March 1833.
  - S. [M. Daingerfield] at Belplain, to Major J. F. Daingerfield, at Richmond, Va. 8 Feb[ruary] 1839.
    Postmarked Warsaw.
  - [S. M. Daingerfield], at Belleplane, to [J. F.] Daingerfield, at Richmond, Virginia. 14 March 1839., Mutilated.
  - S. M. Daingerfield, at Westwood, to her sister, Margaret A. Withrow, at Lewisburg, Greenbrier County, Va. 18 Sept. 1840., Same sheet as below.
    Postmarked Port Republic
  - S. M. Daingerfield to her brother [John Withrow.], Same sheet as above
  - Sally [Daingerfield] to Joseph F. Daingerfield, at Fayette Court House, Va. No date.
    Postmarked Lewisburgh, Va.
  Series 2: Letters of Edward R. Edmunds
- Letters of Edward R. Edmunds. 1850-1851., 2 items.
  - E[dward] R[andolph] Edmunds, at Florence, Italy, to Mrs. E[dwin] S[hort] Edmunds, at Hopkinsville, Ky. 25 June 1850.
  - Edward [R. Edmunds] at London, to Sallie [i.e., Mrs. Edwin S. Edmunds], at Hopkinsville, Ky. 10 Aug. 1851.
  Series 3: Letter concerning West Point record of Joseph F. Daingerfield.
- Copy of a letter from [?] LeR. Martin, assistant adjutant, U. S. Military Academy, West Point, New York, to [Miss Sally Daingerfield 10 Feb[ruary] 1930
  Concerning the record of Joseph F. Daingerfield.